<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>DailyGuide Network</title>
	<atom:link href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com</link>
	<description>Leading News Source in Ghana</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/cropped-dailyguide-icon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>DailyGuide Network</title>
	<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Assemblyman Commits Suicide</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/assemblyman-commits-suicide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assemblyman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Osei kwabena]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; OSEI KWABENA, Assemblyman for Agogo Apentenyinase Electoral Area in Asante Akyem North Municipality in the Ashanti Region, has allegedly committed suicide. According to numerous reports, Osei’s lifeless body was</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/assemblyman-commits-suicide/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/assemblyman-commits-suicide/">Assemblyman Commits Suicide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>OSEI KWABENA, Assemblyman for Agogo Apentenyinase Electoral Area in Asante Akyem North Municipality in the Ashanti Region, has allegedly committed suicide.</p>
<p>According to numerous reports, Osei’s lifeless body was found hanging on a ceiling fan, which was tied to a rope, in his room around 4pm on Wednesday, January 7, 2026.</p>
<p>What may have compelled the assemblyman to end his own life in that bizarre manner was not immediately known as he did not leave behind any note.</p>
<p>His demise is said to have come as a great surprise to the people of Agogo Apentenyinase Electoral Area since he did not show any sign that he was troubled before his death.</p>
<p>According to reports, Osei lives with his wife and he did not show any sign of trouble to her. He allegedly hanged himself after the wife went to the market to purchase foodstuffs.</p>
<p>Confirming the death to journalists, Enoch Osafo Asiedu, the Assemblyman for Obuasi Gyedim Electoral Area in the Asante Akyem North Municipality, stated that “I’m traumatized”.</p>
<p>According to him, Osei called him on phone few days ago, where he (Osei) complained bitterly about how some people in his electoral area were making life difficult for him.</p>
<p>“I traveled to Eastern Region on Friday when Osei called and said there was pressure from people in his electoral area about a petrol station that a certain developer is putting up in his area.</p>
<p>“He said some of his electoral area members were accusing him of taking bribe from the contractor. He sounded a bit disturbed but I managed to calm him down”, Enoch said.</p>
<p>According to him, barely few hours before the incident, he saw Osei riding a bicycle “and it was later in the day that I heard that he had committed suicide in his room”.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the body is said to have been deposited in a morgue for preservation and autopsy to confirm the cause of death, as the police are investigating the suicide incident.</p>
<p><strong>FROM I.F. Joe Awuah </strong><strong>Kumasi</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/assemblyman-commits-suicide/">Assemblyman Commits Suicide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Knew Ebo Noah Was Creating Content – Sarkodie</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/i-knew-ebo-noah-was-creating-content-sarkodie/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newsone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ebo Noah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarkodie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Rapper Sarkodie has broken his silence on the arrest of controversial self-styled prophet, Ebo Noah, insisting the viral figure was merely creating content and not committing a crime. In</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/i-knew-ebo-noah-was-creating-content-sarkodie/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/i-knew-ebo-noah-was-creating-content-sarkodie/">I Knew Ebo Noah Was Creating Content – Sarkodie</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rapper Sarkodie has broken his silence on the arrest of controversial self-styled prophet, Ebo Noah, insisting the viral figure was merely creating content and not committing a crime.</p>
<p>In an Instagram story posted on January 2, 2026, Sarkodie reacted to a circulating video showing Evans Eshun, popularly known as Ebo Noah, in handcuffs as he was escorted into a police vehicle. The rapper questioned the basis of the arrest, suggesting that Ebo Noah’s actions had been misunderstood.</p>
<p>“Don’t know exactly what my boy’s crime is, but from day one I knew he was making content, unless he’s been charged with something else,” Sarkodie wrote, casting doubt on the seriousness of Ebo Noah’s widely publicised prophecy.</p>
<p>Ebo Noah was arrested on Wednesday, December 31, 2025, by the Ghana Police Service after months of nationwide anxiety sparked by his prediction of a catastrophic flood scheduled for December 25, 2025. The prophecy, which drew comparisons to the biblical story of Noah, claimed that a three-year global flood would begin on Christmas Day.</p>
<p>The 33-year-old content creator gained viral attention in late 2025 by documenting himself on TikTok and YouTube as he built wooden “arks” in places such as Elmina and Kumasi. He claimed the vessels were meant to save believers and said he was building up to 10 of them on divine instruction.</p>
<p>When no flood occurred on December 25, Ebo Noah told followers that his prayers and fasting had convinced God to postpone the disaster, a claim that further fuelled public backlash.</p>
<p>Outrage intensified after he appeared on stage at Sarkodie’s Rapperholic 2025 concert on December 25—the same day the predicted flood was expected to begin.</p>
<p>Police later arrested him in the Weija-Gbawe area for allegedly spreading false news and causing fear and panic. On January 2, 2026, the Adentan Circuit Court remanded him into police custody for two weeks and ordered a psychiatric evaluation at the Pantang Psychiatric Hospital.</p>
<p>Ebo Noah is expected to reappear in court on January 16, 2026.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/i-knew-ebo-noah-was-creating-content-sarkodie/">I Knew Ebo Noah Was Creating Content – Sarkodie</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wiyaala To Be Enskinned As Paramount Queenmother Of Funsi</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/wiyaala-to-be-enskinned-as-paramount-queenmother-of-funsi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newsone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wiyaala]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Musician and cultural ambassador, Wiyaala, popularly known as the Lioness of Africa, is set to be enskinned as the Paramount Queenmother of the Funsi Traditional Area in the Upper</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/wiyaala-to-be-enskinned-as-paramount-queenmother-of-funsi/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/wiyaala-to-be-enskinned-as-paramount-queenmother-of-funsi/">Wiyaala To Be Enskinned As Paramount Queenmother Of Funsi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Musician and cultural ambassador, Wiyaala, popularly known as the Lioness of Africa, is set to be enskinned as the Paramount Queenmother of the Funsi Traditional Area in the Upper West Region on January 17, 2026.</p>
<p>The announcement was made by Wiyaala in a public statement in which she disclosed that the enskinment will be performed by the elders and kingsmen of Funsi, following the elevation of the traditional area to paramountcy status. She described the honour as historic, noting that it marks a significant new chapter in the cultural and traditional development of Funsi.</p>
<p>As part of the celebrations, Wiyaala has introduced the Pulung Festival, which will be held on the same day. According to her, the traditional enskinment ceremony will take place in the morning, while the festival will be staged later in the evening.</p>
<p>The cultural and musical festival is scheduled to begin at 6:30 p.m. and will feature performances by a wide range of artistes and cultural groups, including Wiyaala, Gally, Samson B, The Yaga Yagas, Savage Dancers from Slovenia, B-Prince, F-Boy, Saadia, Apaco, Iron Bwoy, the Boys and Girls Club, the Chansiye Dance Group, and the Chansiye Women Group, among others.</p>
<p>In a separate public notice, the elders and kingsmen of the Funsi Paramountcy confirmed that Wiyaala will be formally introduced and enskinned as the Paramount Queenmother on the stated date. The ceremony and associated events will be hosted at the Wiyaala Art Centre in Funsi.</p>
<p>Organisers have extended an open invitation to members of the public, both within and outside the Funsi Traditional Area, to participate in what is expected to be a major cultural milestone for the community.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/wiyaala-to-be-enskinned-as-paramount-queenmother-of-funsi/">Wiyaala To Be Enskinned As Paramount Queenmother Of Funsi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regina Daniels Takes Drug Test After Months of Allegations</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/regina-daniels-takes-drug-test-after-months-of-allegations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newsone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nesone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regina Daniels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Nigerian actress Regina Daniels has gone to hospital to take a drug test following months of public accusations of substance abuse. In a short Instagram video, Regina said, “Hi</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/regina-daniels-takes-drug-test-after-months-of-allegations/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/regina-daniels-takes-drug-test-after-months-of-allegations/">Regina Daniels Takes Drug Test After Months of Allegations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Nigerian actress Regina Daniels has gone to hospital to take a drug test following months of public accusations of substance abuse.</p>
<p>In a short Instagram video, Regina said, “Hi guys, so I’m here at the hospital, I’m about to run my drug test,” as she showed herself at the medical facility.</p>
<p>The development comes nearly three months after her husband, Senator Ned Nwoko, accused her of drug use while denying her claims of domestic violence made in October 2025.</p>
<p>The situation became more controversial when her co-wife, Laila Charani, alleged that Regina introduced her to drugs. An alleged medical report also surfaced online, claiming Regina tested positive for several substances.</p>
<p>Serenity Royale Hospital later denied leaking any such medical report and asked the public to ignore it.</p>
<p>Regina’s decision to take the drug test is seen as a response to the ongoing allegations surrounding her personal life.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/regina-daniels-takes-drug-test-after-months-of-allegations/">Regina Daniels Takes Drug Test After Months of Allegations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK-Ghana Remittances Drop To 17.5%</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/uk-ghana-remittances-drop-to-17-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dr johnson asiama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK-Ghana Remittances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483915</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Johnson Asiama, Christian Rogg and other stakeholders &#160; Remittance inflows from the United Kingdom accounted for ONLY 17.5 percent of total remittance receipts marking a decline from 27.6 percent</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/uk-ghana-remittances-drop-to-17-5/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/uk-ghana-remittances-drop-to-17-5/">UK-Ghana Remittances Drop To 17.5%</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dr. Johnson Asiama, Christian Rogg and other stakeholders</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Remittance inflows from the United Kingdom accounted for ONLY 17.5 percent of total remittance receipts marking a decline from 27.6 percent in 2024 given that the Ghanaian diaspora in the United Kingdom represent a major remittance corridor.</p>
<p>The Governor of the Bank of Ghana (BoG), Dr. Johnson Asiama who disclosed this at the maiden London–Accra Economic Growth Summit said remittances constitute a structurally important and countercyclical source of foreign exchange for the country.</p>
<p>“During the period January–September 2025, remittance inflows from the UK accounted for 17.5 percent of total remittance receipts. This proportion marks a decline compared to the corresponding period in 2024, when the UK corridor contributed 27.6 percent, equivalent to more than one quarter of total inflows,” he said.</p>
<p>London–Accra Economic Growth Summit was officially launched in July 2025 with the Mayor of London, Sir Sadiq Khan, as part of a campaign to strengthen economic cooperation between Ghana and the United Kingdom through meaningful diaspora engagement.</p>
<p>Dr. Asiama also stated that there is considerable scope to scale up remittance inflows from the UK through the implementation of well-targeted policy measures and incentive-based frameworks adding that Diaspora inflows must be harnessed beyond consumption and deliberately channeled into sustainable investment that drives long-term growth.</p>
<p>The flows, he explained, have played a vital role in supporting household consumption, strengthened balance of payments, and enhanced macroeconomic stability.</p>
<p>“However, beyond consumption, remittances hold even greater potential as a driver of productive investment. When strategically channelled, they can finance small and medium-sized enterprises expand housing, modernise agriculture and, in doing so, create sustainable employment for young people through knowledge and skills transfer programmes at the national and local levels,” he noted.</p>
<p>The Governor mentioned that the Central Bank will soon roll out many targeted interventions including the development of the National Remittance Strategy in close collaboration with the Ministry of Finance, as well as a Remittance Road show to advance inclusive, continent-wide engagement with diasporans.</p>
<p>“I am calling on all stakeholders, including development partners and our diaspora leaders – let&#8217;s work together deliberately and decisively to transform remittances from simple transfers into powerful engines of growth, resilience and shared prosperity”.</p>
<p>“By deepening our markets, strengthening our institutions, and mobilising diaspora capital through credible and transparent frameworks, we can build a more resilient, investment-driven future for Ghana,” he emphasised.</p>
<p><strong>By Ebenezer K, Amponsah</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/uk-ghana-remittances-drop-to-17-5/">UK-Ghana Remittances Drop To 17.5%</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inflation FallsTo 5.4%</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/inflation-fallsto-5-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. Alhassan Iddrisu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inflation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Alhassan Iddrisu &#160; The country’s downward inflation trend continued its steady decline in December 2025, falling to 5.4 percent year on year, new data from the Ghana Statistical Service</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/inflation-fallsto-5-4/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/inflation-fallsto-5-4/">Inflation FallsTo 5.4%</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dr. Alhassan Iddrisu</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The country’s downward inflation trend continued its steady decline in December 2025, falling to 5.4 percent year on year, new data from the Ghana Statistical Service has shown.</p>
<p>The decline marks the 12<sup>th</sup> consecutive month of disinflation and the lowest rate since the Consumer Price Index (CPI) was rebased in 2021.</p>
<p>Government Statistician, Dr. Alhassan Iddrisu, presenting the latest inflation figures in Accra, yesterday, said the CPI for December 2025 stood at 261.7, up from 240.8 in December 2024, translating into a significant moderation in price pressures over the year.</p>
<p>This he said meant that, on average, goods and services cost 5.4 percent more than they did in December 2024.</p>
<p>“This result is significant because inflation has now declined for 12 consecutive months. It fell from 6.3 percent in November 2025 and from 23.8 percent in December 2024, representing a reduction of 18.4 percentage points within a year,” he explained.</p>
<p>Dr. Iddrisu further noted that the sustained decline, points to improving macroeconomic conditions and a firm shift towards price stability.</p>
<p>On a month-on-month basis, inflation stood at 0.9 percent in December 2025, indicating a marginal increase in prices between November and December with Dr. Iddrisu explaining that while short-term price movements persist, they are now occurring within a stable and downward long-term trend.</p>
<p>Dr. Iddrisu said price pressures eased across food, non-food, goods, and both locally produced and imported items, compared to both November 2025 and December 2024.</p>
<p>Food inflation also recorded a sharp decline on an annual basis, falling to 4.9 percent in December 2025, down from 6.6 percent in November 2025 and 27.8 percent in December 2024, representing a 22.9 percentage point drop over the year.</p>
<p>“This matters because food accounts for about 43 percent of household spending. Lower food inflation directly eases pressure on household budgets,” Dr. Iddrisu noted.</p>
<p>However, he cautioned that food prices still rose by 1.1 percent month on month, suggesting that while long-term pressures have eased, short-term fluctuations remain, largely driven by seasonal factors.</p>
<p>Non-food inflation also declined significantly, easing to 5.8 percent in December, from 6.1 percent in November and 20.3 percent a year earlier, reflecting a 14.5 percentage point reduction over the year. On a monthly basis, non-food prices increased by 0.6 percent, indicating moderate pressure.</p>
<p>“These trends show broad-based disinflation across both food and non-food categories, rather than improvements driven by a single component,” Dr. Iddrisu said.</p>
<p>The data also revealed a strong slowdown in goods inflation, which fell to 5.8 percent in December 2025, down from 7.3 percent in November and 23.1 percent in December 2024. This represents a 17.3 percentage point reduction over the year.</p>
<p>“Goods account for nearly three-quarters of the CPI basket, so this slowdown provides relief where it matters most to consumers,” he said.</p>
<p>Goods prices increased by 0.8 percent month on month, while services inflation edged up slightly to 4.5 percent in December, from 3.8 percent in November. Despite the increase, services inflation remains well below its 15.4 percent level in December 2024, marking a 10.9 percentage point decline over the year.</p>
<p>Month-on-month, services prices rose by 0.9 percent between November and December 2025.</p>
<p><strong>A Business Desk Report</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/inflation-fallsto-5-4/">Inflation FallsTo 5.4%</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Be Independent In Your Operations- Otumfuo To BoG</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/be-independent-in-your-operations-otumfuo-to-bog/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank Of Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Otumfuo Osei Tutu II]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Johnson Asiama interacting with Asantehene Otumfuo Osei Tutu II &#160; The Asantehene, Otumfuo Osei Tutu II, has called on political parties to refrain from interfering in the operations of</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/be-independent-in-your-operations-otumfuo-to-bog/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/be-independent-in-your-operations-otumfuo-to-bog/">Be Independent In Your Operations- Otumfuo To BoG</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dr. Johnson Asiama interacting with Asantehene Otumfuo Osei Tutu II</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Asantehene, Otumfuo Osei Tutu II, has called on political parties to refrain from interfering in the operations of the Bank of Ghana (BoG) given its role in safeguarding the country’s financial stability.</p>
<p>Otumfuo Osei Tutu II who made the call during a courtesy visit to the Governor of the Bank of Ghana, Dr. Johnson Asiama, at the Bank&#8217;s Square in Accra, said insulating the BoG from political strings will enable the Central Bank achieve its mandate.</p>
<p>“This is a unique institution with a mandate that ultimately affects every citizen of the land. Ideally, this citadel should be a fortress insulated from the strings and arrows of the political warfare. Whatever it is, we should think twice before we do anything that has the capacity to cast a snare on the integrity of the bank,” the Otumfuo said.</p>
<p>“I will appeal to the nation and both sides of the political divide to give the Governor, my son and his team a chance, give them the space and respect to perform their professional duties. Support them along the right path and offer counsel necessary for the good of the Bank. This is our bank, we have entrusted to them, if they fail, we risk collapse, if they succeed, we walk in wealth and in glory,” the Asantehene noted.</p>
<p>The visit was intended to offer Otumfuo Osei Tutu II a firsthand understanding of BoG&#8217;s role in stabilising the economy, ensuring price stability, and protecting the country’s financial system.</p>
<p>While commending the management of the Central Bank for various policies that has helped transformed the economy, the Asantehene also encouraged the Bank of Ghana to continue to communicate in a language that resonates with the public while explaining policies in simple terms that all Ghanaians would understand.</p>
<p>“It is a fact of history that when the currency is healthy, the economy bristles with opportunities, the people are able to use the opportunities to create business the business allows the people to create jobs and ultimately walk in wealth, when the Cedi wobbles even the Tsunami can be less destructive,” the Asantehene noted.</p>
<p>Reflecting on the past year, Otumfuo Osei Tutu II  stated that though the cedi has shown signs of stabilisation after a challenging period, it should be recognised as an early sign of progress that need not to be celebrated before the full scope of the harvest while acknowledging and urging the Central Bank to maintain the trajectory.</p>
<p>The Asantehene further asked the leadership of the Bank of Ghana to focus on transitioning the economy from high interest rates to a more favorable environment that promotes business and wealth creation.</p>
<p>&#8220;No amount of foreign investment can solve our economic challenges unless we address the crippling high interest rates,&#8221; he stated. He called for a massive push to stimulate domestic private investment and industry, which he said cannot thrive under current interest rate levels.</p>
<p>Governor of the Bank of Ghana, Dr. Johnson Asiama for his part assured Ghanaians that the Central Bank is committed to maintaining macroeconomic stability, strengthening monetary discipline, and restoring confidence in the financial sector while acknowledging the challenges facing the country.</p>
<p><strong>By Ebenezer K. Amponsah</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/be-independent-in-your-operations-otumfuo-to-bog/">Be Independent In Your Operations- Otumfuo To BoG</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fighting The Public, Not The Fires</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/fighting-the-public-not-the-fires/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana national fire service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; At a time when we should be commenting on critical national issues that would ensure good governance, we have been compelled to take a look at a crude and</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/fighting-the-public-not-the-fires/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/fighting-the-public-not-the-fires/">Fighting The Public, Not The Fires</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At a time when we should be commenting on critical national issues that would ensure good governance, we have been compelled to take a look at a crude and uncivilised conduct by firefighters as it unfolded at Kasoa last Monday.</p>
<p>Ghana joined hands to condemn the antiquated brutality meted out on a lone journalist by some personnel of the Ghana National Fire Service (GNFS).</p>
<p>It was an imbecilic act of shame when persons who responded to an emergency call to save lives and properties turned out to rather, as it were, become rogues whose actions could have killed instead of save the persons they are remunerated by the state to protect.</p>
<p>Ghana has put that outmoded baggage of uniformed personnel attacking their compatriots outside the regimented order behind her back. The last time such brutish conduct took place was in Tamale when a student of the Tamale Technical University was assaulted by a policeman during a students’ demonstration.</p>
<p>In any case, firefighters are not known to behave like hounds or hogs as they did at Kasoa.</p>
<p>If the misconduct of the first responders at the fire scene disheartened Ghanaians, the response from the Public Relations (PR) Unit of the GNFS did worst bereft of wisdom. Whoever crafted the response did so without an idea of how to manage image crisis.</p>
<p>Claiming that the defaulting personnel were assaulting a thief opens the GNFS for further public opprobrium. Must a suspected thief be hit on the head with protective helmets the way the viral video showed on social media? Was that how the defaulters were trained at the Fire Training School? Is that nonsense part of firefighting drill? And the PR Unit put out that ‘crap’ of a response without the Chief Fire Officer reading it before letting out on the public domain?</p>
<p>It is instructive that even before assaulting the poor <strong><em>Class FM</em></strong> reporter, the firefighters had already been engaged in an altercation with some persons around the fire scene. It just shows that a bunch of undisciplined firefighters were deployed to the fire scene, leaving us to deal with the rotten outcome.</p>
<p>We find it amazing that after defending the action of the personnel, the GNFS turns round to tell us that they are investigating the misconduct.</p>
<p>There was nothing wrong with videoing the misconduct of the defaulters by the reporter, which incensed the first responders. If the misconduct is acceptable, why were the defaulters scared of the public having a look at what transpired anyway.</p>
<p>Let us not allow a situation where when firefighters respond to an emergency they turn their hoses and helmets on victims and others as tools of assault rather than tools for putting fires and saving lives and properties.</p>
<p>While we do not have confidence in the outcome of the enquiry being conducted by management of the GNFS, we nonetheless demand that an apology be rendered to Ghanaians even before the report is released.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/fighting-the-public-not-the-fires/">Fighting The Public, Not The Fires</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Killed In Bia Accident</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/6-killed-in-bia-accident/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accident]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The accident scene &#160; Six (6) people reportedly died on the spot in a tragic road accident at Asikuma, a community located between Bia West and Bia East districts in</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/6-killed-in-bia-accident/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/6-killed-in-bia-accident/">6 Killed In Bia Accident</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The accident scene</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Six (6) people reportedly died on the spot in a tragic road accident at Asikuma, a community located between Bia West and Bia East districts in the Western North Region.</p>
<p>The accident has left one other person in critical condition.</p>
<p>It was reported that eight persons, including the rider, were onboard a tricycle, popularly known as &#8216;Aboboya&#8217;, which was moving from Asuopiri in the Bia West District to Adabokrom in the Bia East District for farming activities.</p>
<p>Upon reaching a sloping section of the road near Asikuma, a timber truck travelling from Adabokrom reportedly lost control and crashed into the tricycle, killing the six people instantly.</p>
<p>The victim who sustained severe injuries was rushed to the Assamu Government Hospital for medical treatment.</p>
<p>Information gathered was that the rider of the tricycle managed to jump off and escape moments before the crash, but currently, his whereabouts remain unknown.</p>
<p>Youth in the community have since mounted a search to locate him and ascertain his condition.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the driver of the timber truck has reported himself to the Debiso District Police Command.</p>
<p>Personnel from the Command visited the scene, conveyed the bodies to the morgue, and have since commenced investigations into the accident.</p>
<p><strong>From Emmanuel Opoku, Takoradi</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/6-killed-in-bia-accident/">6 Killed In Bia Accident</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ken Ofori-Atta Detained By U.S. Immigration Authorities</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-ofori-atta-detained-by-u-s-immigration-authorities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ken Ofori-Atta]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ken Ofori-Atta &#160; The United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) has detained former Finance Minister, Ken Ofori-Atta for questioning over the status of his stay in the country. This</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-ofori-atta-detained-by-u-s-immigration-authorities/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-ofori-atta-detained-by-u-s-immigration-authorities/">Ken Ofori-Atta Detained By U.S. Immigration Authorities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ken Ofori-Atta</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) has detained former Finance Minister, Ken Ofori-Atta for questioning over the status of his stay in the country.</p>
<p>This was confirmed by his legal team in a public statement circulated in the media.</p>
<p>According to the statement released on January 7, 2026, Mr Ofori-Atta is currently cooperating fully with ICE while his lawyers engage the authorities to resolve the issue as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The statement explained that Mr Ofori-Atta has a pending petition for adjustment of status, a process under US law that allows an individual to remain legally in the country beyond the validity of an initial visa.</p>
<p>His legal team says this is a common immigration procedure and expects the matter to be resolved expeditiously.</p>
<p>The statement stressed that Mr Ofori-Atta remains a law-abiding individual and is working closely with US immigration authorities to regularise his status while continuing his medical recovery.</p>
<p>His stay in the US has been marred by an ongoing legal issue in Ghana. In November 2025, the Office of the Special Prosecutor (OSP) charged him and others with corruption and corruption-related offences.</p>
<p>The case is currently at the case management conference stage.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-ofori-atta-detained-by-u-s-immigration-authorities/">Ken Ofori-Atta Detained By U.S. Immigration Authorities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCHES ALL PRESIDENTS&#8230;24/7</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/watches-all-presidents-24-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AKOSUA CARTOON]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/watches-all-presidents-24-7/">WATCHES ALL PRESIDENTS&#8230;24/7</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/watches-all-presidents-24-7/">WATCHES ALL PRESIDENTS&#8230;24/7</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samira Cries Foul Over Bawumia Smear Campaign</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/samira-cries-foul-over-bawumia-smear-campaign/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dr mahamudu bawumia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NPP Presidential Premiers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samira bawumia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Samira Bawumia  &#160; FORMER SECOND Lady, Samira Bawumia, has openly expressed gross worry over how her husband and ex-Vice President, Dr.  Mahamudu Bawumia, is being smeared by his own party</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/samira-cries-foul-over-bawumia-smear-campaign/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/samira-cries-foul-over-bawumia-smear-campaign/">Samira Cries Foul Over Bawumia Smear Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Samira Bawumia </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>FORMER SECOND Lady, Samira Bawumia, has openly expressed gross worry over how her husband and ex-Vice President, Dr.  Mahamudu Bawumia, is being smeared by his own party members because of an impending internal poll.</p>
<p>According to Samira, her husband, who is seeking to retain his position as the New Patriotic Party (NPP) presidential candidate for the 2028 general election, is being lied about by his political opponents without any justification.</p>
<p>For instance, Samira bemoaned that some of the NPP presidential candidates have labeled Dr. Bawumia as being a member of the ruling National Democratic Congress (NDC), an accusation she finds it difficult to understand.</p>
<p>The former Second Lady, who did not mention names, recounted that just one year ago these same people who are now labeling Dr. Bawumia as an NDC member, were singing his (Bawumia) praises when he led NPP in the 2024 polls.</p>
<p>“They are on a lying spree presently, they have lied and lied to the extent that they are now saying that Dr. Mahamudu Bawumia, our former Vice President on the ticket of the great NPP, is an ardent NDC member, is it not surprising?” she quizzed.</p>
<p>“During the 2024 national elections, these same people described Dr. Bawumia as very intelligent, peaceful, hardworking and a visionary leader, who has what it takes to positively change Ghana’s fortunes in a short time.</p>
<p>“What has changed in just one year that Dr. Bawumia is now being smeared and crucified by his own party members because of an impending party election on January 31, 2026?” Samira, who looked worried, asked her audience.</p>
<p>According to her, all the negative things that are being said about Dr. Bawumia are palpable lies, which have no basis, therefore the party delegates should treat them with the contempt that they deserve and vote for her husband.</p>
<p>Addressing NPP members in the Tafo Constituency in Kumasi, in the Ashanti Region during a campaign tour, Samira urged the party members to remain calm and stay united even as the election to elect a presidential candidate approaches.</p>
<p>Samira reminded the NPP members that after the January 31, 2026 election, the NPP would have to unite as one family with a common destiny to confront the 2028 elections, stressing that they should work hard to sustain party unity regardless.</p>
<p>She concluded that Dr. Bawumia is well marketed and also has the wherewithal to lead the NPP to snatch political power from the NDC in 2028, and urged the NPP delegates, who are the kingmakers in the party, to vote massively for him.</p>
<p><strong>FROM I.F. Joe Awuah, Kumasi</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/samira-cries-foul-over-bawumia-smear-campaign/">Samira Cries Foul Over Bawumia Smear Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ken Is The Leader Ghana Wants &#8211; Naa Torshie</title>
		<link>https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-is-the-leader-ghana-wants-naa-torshie/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Frimpong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irene Naa Torshie Addo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ken agyapong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kennedy Ohene Agyapong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NPP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dailyguidenetwork.com/?p=483893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kennedy Ohene Agyapong &#160; Former Administrator of the District Assemblies Common Fund (DACF), Irene Naa Torshie Addo, says Ghanaians across the country are calling on the New Patriotic Party (NPP)</p>
<div><a class="permalink" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-is-the-leader-ghana-wants-naa-torshie/">Read More...</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-is-the-leader-ghana-wants-naa-torshie/">Ken Is The Leader Ghana Wants &#8211; Naa Torshie</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kennedy Ohene Agyapong</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Former Administrator of the District Assemblies Common Fund (DACF), Irene Naa Torshie Addo, says Ghanaians across the country are calling on the New Patriotic Party (NPP) to present Kennedy Ohene Agyapong as its presidential candidate for the 2028 general election.</p>
<p>According to her, the calls reflect a growing public desire for a courageous, honest and decisive leader who is untainted by corruption and prepared to take bold decisions in the national interest.</p>
<p>Madam Addo made the remarks yesterday during her Eastern Regional tour, where she is engaging party delegates and supporters across all 33 constituencies as part of ongoing consultations ahead of the NPP’s presidential primaries.</p>
<p>“The feedback from the people is clear. Ghanaians want a leader who is fearless, truthful and decisive. Ken Agyapong represents that leadership,” she stated.</p>
<p>She explained that many citizens, including floating voters, see Kennedy Agyapong as a forthright politician who consistently speaks against wrongdoing and stands firmly for accountability.</p>
<p>According to Madam Addo, the New Patriotic Party’s path to victory in 2028 will depend largely on its ability to align its internal decisions with the expectations of the wider electorate.</p>
<p>“Ghanaians are calling on the NPP to present Ken Agyapong because they believe he has the courage and integrity to lead this country,” she added.</p>
<p>She urged NPP delegates to listen to the voices of ordinary Ghanaians and support a candidate who can unite the party, energise the grassroots and appeal broadly across the country.</p>
<p>Madam Addo stressed that presenting a bold and credible leader in 2028 would be key to restoring public confidence and returning the NPP to power.</p>
<p>Her Eastern Regional engagements form part of broader campaign and consultation activities as the party prepares for internal processes ahead of the next general election cycle.</p>
<p><strong>A Daily Guide Report</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com/ken-is-the-leader-ghana-wants-naa-torshie/">Ken Is The Leader Ghana Wants &#8211; Naa Torshie</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://dailyguidenetwork.com">DailyGuide Network</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
